Gerry Mulligan Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music (Box 1-148, 160)
  - Waller-in
    - Lead sheet, On folder: Carriage House Date 3/14/89 (Box-folder 22/7)
  - Wallflower
    - Score; lead sheet, On folder: Carriage House Date 3/14/89 (Box-folder 22/62)
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Part (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
    - Lead sheet, Originally filed with "Franca Arrivo" folder (B 135) (Box-folder 21/12)
  - Wallington's Godchild
    - Score; parts (tentet) (Box-folder 139/4)
    - Score and parts, On folder: Score of original Miles Davis version written for Smithsonian (Box-folder 136/8)
    - Score (5 horns); sketch, On folder: Score of original Miles Davis version written for Smithsonian (Box-folder 136/8)
    - Parts (tentet), From "Gig books" (Box-folder 111/2)
    - Parts (miscellaneous) (Box-folder 160/6)
  - Waltz euphoria, Ross Schneider
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 23/6)
  - Waltzing Matilda
    - Score (big band) (Box-folder 135/5)
    - Parts (rhythm section), GM personal performance parts (Box-folder 116)
    - Parts (big band) (Box-folder 52/7)
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Part (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
  - Wand'ring
    - Lead sheet, On folder: New quartet, 6/24/94 (Box-folder 23A/1)
  - Warm valley, Duke Ellington
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 16/7)
  - Watching and waiting, From the 1977 film La menace
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 18/8)
  - Waterworks
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 24/5)
  - Wave, Antonio Carlos Jobim
    - Lead sheet; part (baritone saxophone), For the 1994 recording Paraiso (Box-folder 23/8)
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 23A/13)
  - We lost out way, Alec Wilder
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 18/1)
  - We never talk much
    - Conductor's score; parts (Concert Jazz Band), Al Cohn arrangement for Judy Holliday recording (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band), Al Cohn arrangement (Box-folder 145/1)
  - A weed in Disneyland
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 133/14)
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 52/4)
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 9/3)
  - Weep, Gary McFarland
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band), Gary McFarland arrangement (Box-folder 33/4)
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band), Gary McFarland arrangement (Box-folder 145/12)
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Welcome home
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Parts (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
    - Parts, GM personal performance parts (Box-folder 116)
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 17/1)
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 18/8)
  - Well, git it!
    - Score (orchestra), John Bambridge arrangement for Cincinatti Pops concert (Box-folder 148/6)
  - Western reunion
    - Parts (sextet) (Box-folder 65/7)
    - Parts, On folder: Small band trumpet parts (Box-folder 66/2)
    - Lead sheet, On folder: Misc. sextet parts (Box-folder 19/1)
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Western Telesong 1 and 2
    - Score (trumpet 1/2, tenor 1/2, bass, drums) (Box-folder 145/5)
    - Parts (trumpet 1/2, tenor 1/2, bass, drums) (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Westwood walk
    - Score; parts (tentet), From "Gig books" (Box-folder 112/6)
    - Photocopied score and parts (tentet) (Box-folder 139/3)
  - What am I doing here?, Barry Manilow
    - Lead sheet; parts (piano, drums, baritone saxophone) (Box-folder 19/4)
  - What is there to say?, Vernon Duke
    - Score (transcription), Transcription by Mark Lopeman (Box-folder 62/11)
    - Parts (quartet), On folder: Quartet with Art Farmer, Lincoln Center '94, The art of trumpet (Box-folder 139/10)
    - Parts (piano, bass, bari saxophone), On folder: Art Farmer, Lincoln Center '94, The art of trumpet (Box-folder 24/1)
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Part (bass), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
  - What's the matter with me?
    - Sketch; lyric sheets (Box-folder 14/3)
  - What's the rush
    - Score (Concert Jazz Band), Bob Brookmeyer arrangement for Judy Holliday recording (Box-folder 147/5)
    - Score, For Dublin Radio Eire, 1970 (Box-folder 57/2)
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band), Bob Brookmeyer arrangement for Judy Holliday recording (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Part (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
    - Lead sheet; lyric sheets, Lyrics in the hand of Judy Holliday (Box-folder 12/7)
  - When I'm sixty-four
    - Parts (rhythm, melody, harmony), From "Standards" folder (Box-folder 18/19)
  - When love is gone, Barry Manilow
    - Lead sheet; parts (piano, baritone saxophone), From "Standards" folder (Box-folder 19/4)
  - When October goes, Barry Manilow
    - Lead sheet; parts (piano, baritone saxophone) (Box-folder 19/4)
  - When rabbit runs
    - Parts (baritone saxophone), From "Brubeck parts" folder (Box-folder 82/1)
  - When the saints go marching in, James Milton Black
    - Score; sketch, Jeff Tyzik arrangement for Cincinnatti Pops concert (Box-folder 148/6)
  - When you and I were young, Maggie
    - Lead sheet, Dated: Nov. 1951 (Box-folder 56/8)
    - Sketch (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Where have you gone?, Barry Manilow
    - Lead sheet; parts (baritone saxophone) (Box-folder 19/4)
  - Where or when, Richard Rodgers / Lorenz Hart
    - Score (big band), Dated: 2/52; On folder: For Kenton (Box-folder 133/8)
  - Where was I?
    - Lead sheet; lyric sheets, Lyrics by Mary Brill (Box-folder 18/16)
  - Where's the child?, Alec Wilder
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 18/1)
  - While we're young, Alec Wilder
    - Score (big band) (Box-folder 145/4)
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band), Bill Finnegan arrangement for Judy Holliday recording (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Whistlin' blues
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Lead sheet, On folder: GM tunes/lead sheets, returned by Dave Brubeck, May 1984 (Box-folder 82/2)
  - Whistlin' tune
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Who could care?, Bob Brookmeyer
    - Parts, Incomplete (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Why are you blue?, Gary Mcfarland
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Why not mood
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 21/4)
  - Wild Bill
    - Lead sheet, On folder: New songs for quartet 2-9-93, originals (Box-folder 23/12)
  - Willow tree
    - Lead sheet; lyric sheets, Lyrics by Jane Duboc (Box-folder 23/8)
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 24/2)
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 23A/9)
  - Willow weep for me, Ann Ronell
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band), Piano and trumpet 4 parts are missing (Box-folder 38/6)
  - Willows
    - Parts (extra baritone saxophone) (Box-folder 80/2)
    - Lead sheet, From "Misc. works, some for Count Basie Band" folder (Box-folder 19/3)
    - Lead sheet; parts (bass, drums, piano), Multiple titles: "Willows" and "Willows - Reaper" (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Windfall, Manny Albam
    - Baritone saxophone part, On folder: Wilder winds concert (Box-folder 81/14)
  - With a smile on my face
    - Parts (rhythm section), GM personal performance parts (Box-folder 116)
    - Lead sheet with lyrics (Box-folder 15/8)
    - Lead sheet, For the Mel Tormé vocal compilation "Tentet with Tormé" (Box-folder 62/6)
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 18/18)
  - With a smile on your face
    - Sketch score, For John Dankworth band (Box-folder 131/7)
    - Score (big band), Dated: Jan. 27, 1981 (Box-folder 131/8)
    - Score; sketch score (big band), On score, the title "Sandy" is crossed out; on sketch, the title "Sweet Pea" (Billy "Sweet Pea" Strayhorn), is crossed out (Box-folder 145/14)
    - Parts (big band) (Box-folder 48/3)
  - Wombat
    - Sketches; parts (alto saxophone), GM notebook "for Brubeck and Desmond" (Box-folder 53/5)
  - Wondering
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 18/9)
    - Lead sheet, On verso of "Wand'ring"; On folder: New quartet, 6/24/94 (Box-folder 23A/1)
  - Wood on wood
    - Lead sheet; parts (piano, bass, drums), On verso of bass part: Progression for "Angelica" (Box-folder 15/4)
    - Printed solo collection (Box-folder 15/4)
    - Parts, On folder: Quartet trumpet parts - originals (Box-folder 66/7)
    - Parts, On folder: GM parts, Kelly and Mike's tunes (Box-folder 67/7)
    - Part (piano), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 114)
    - Part (bass, drums), From the Gerry Mulligan Quartet road book (Box-folder 115)
  - Woody'n you, Dizzy Gillespie
    - Parts (trumpet 1/2, tenor saxophone, piano) (Box-folder 56/1)
    - Parts (trumpet 1/2, tenor saxophone, piano), Chico O'Farrill arrangement (Box-folder 58/7)
  - Word to the wise
    - Sketches; lyric notes (Box-folder 21/9)
  - Workaholic at ease blues
    - Lead sheets, From studio session with Scott Hamilton for the recording Soft lights and sweet music (Box-folder 19/17)
  - Wynton, Simon Pilbrow
    - Lead sheet, Note in GM's music library: Some good tunes from an Australian (Box-folder 22/24)
  - X-mas '81
    - Lead sheet, On folder: new quartet, 6/24/94 (Box-folder 23A/1)
  - XXX
    - Score; parts (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 146/3)
  - Yardbird suite, Charlie Parker
    - Score (reduced, unfinished), Inscription: Bird you'll have to do something with the last chorus - I couldn't finish it; On folder: Scored for Bird with strings (most likely for Apollo Theatre) (Box-folder 132/8)
  - Yesterday I loved you, Alec Wilder
    - Lead sheet (Box-folder 18/1)
  - You took advantage of me
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band), Bob Brookmeyer arrangement (Box-folder 46/3)
  - Young blood, For Stan Kenton
    - Score; parts (big band) (Box-folder 55/2)
    - Score; parts (big band), Second version (Box-folder 132/7)
    - Score (big band), Dated: March 1960 (Box-folder 132/7)
    - Parts (Concert Jazz Band) (Box-folder 32/1)
    - Parts (big band), Second version (Box-folder 55/1)
  - You've gotta know yourself, brother
    - Lead sheet with lyrics (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Zoot soot
    - Parts (big band) (Box-folder 61/1)
- Miscellany (Box 5-6, 24-25, 53, 84, 149-159)
  - Band folders
    - Folders (empty) (Box 149)
    - Folder - old quartet book (empty) (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Book
    - Raskin, Ruby. Technical Handbook of Mathematics for Motion Picture Music Synchronization. 2nd ed. R-Y Publishing Co., 1972 (Box-folder 24/6)
  - Click track info - metronome equivalents; holograph notes (Box-folder 24/6)
  - Lists
    - Concert Jazz Band library tunes (Box-folder 25/1)
    - Concert Jazz Band programs (Box-folder 25/1)
    - Concert Jazz Band rehearsals (Box-folder 25/1)
    - Lists, itinerary (1978-1994) (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Tune lists (SS Norway; Concord record date; Scott Hamilton) (Box-folder 53/6)
    - Orchestral instrument parts list, itinerary (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Program lists - quartet concerts (Box-folder 25/1)
    - Tune list for Annie Ross (Box-folder 53/6)
  - Miscellany
    - Artwork, awards, clippings, printed materials, programs (Box 152)
  - Photographs
    - Approximately seventy black and white or color photographs; negatives, Mulligan alone or with friends, and photographs of other performers (Box 150-151)
  - Realia
    - Hat (Box 153)
    - Scarf (paisley, blue and burgandy) (Box 154)
    - Scarf (white) (Box 155)
    - Pen, mechanical pencil, eraser (Box 156)
    - Eye glasses and case (Box 157)
    - Metal miniature train (Box 158)
    - Model airplane (Box 159)
  - Scripts sent to Gerry Mulligan
    - Typed scripts, Titles: "Hugger Mugger in the Louvre" by Pat Reeves, John Greenleaf; "Jesu" by John Esposito; "The Kilgo run" by Arnold Sundgaard; "Son Long!" by Leopold Atlas (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Typed scripts, Titles: "Virginie et Tristan" ou "A duex minutes pres," Denise Petitdidier, producer; "Who is Goldberg?" by Marius Constant (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Typed scripts, Titles: "Play with fire" by Dale Wasserman; "Foley Square" by Diane English; "OSA" by Oleg Egorov (Box-folder 6/1)
Appendix: Index of Arrangers in the Gerry Mulligan Collection
Albam, Manny
Arnold, Hubert
Bambridge, John
Boras, Tom
Brookmeyer, Bob
Brown, Earle
Burns, Ralph
Byers, Billy
Carisi, John
Carubia, Mike
Cohn, Al
Comer, Ed
Dankworth, John
DeRosa, Richard
Donovan, Bob
Evans, Gil
Fay, Thomas
Feller, Sid
Finckel, Ed
Finnegan, Bill
Forman, Mitchel
Francesconi, Luca
Freedman, Robert
Grusin, Dave
Haggart, Bob
Hampton, Slide
Handy, George
Holman, Bill
Kellaway, Roger
Lee, Julian
Lewis, John
Lopeman, Mark
Mandel, Johnny
McFarland, Gary
Mulligan, Gerry
Mundy, Jimmy
Murtaugh, John
Niehaus, Lennie
O'Farrill, Chico
Petracchi, Franco
Sauter, Eddie
Scott, Tom
Stitzel, Mel
Sultanof, Jeff
Sunkel, Phil
Tyzik, Jeff
Thorne, Ken
Woodman, Britt